<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Eric's blog - tech</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/tech.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2022-03-10T08:55:00-03:00</updated><entry><title>Inbox zero</title><link href="/inbox-zero.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2022-03-10T08:55:00-03:00</published><updated>2022-03-10T08:55:00-03:00</updated><author><name>Eric Macedo</name></author><id>tag:None,2022-03-10:/inbox-zero.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing that makes a big difference in my work life is knowing how to process emails. 
I remember having an email inbox full of old emails that I did not need anymore. I used to miss emails a lot, and that used to happen because I was kind of …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing that makes a big difference in my work life is knowing how to process emails. 
I remember having an email inbox full of old emails that I did not need anymore. I used to miss emails a lot, and that used to happen because I was kind of using my email as a to-do list.
Now my inbox is always clean, and I get less distracted (and waste less time) when checking emails.
What I did/do summarises in the steps below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clean your inbox with a Fresh Start:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;**&lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/2006/01/04/email-dmz"&gt;Fresh Start: The Email DMZ&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Start here by cleaning your inbox &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintain your inbox clean:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I always unsubscribe to any marketing emails, newsletters I don’t read. If you don’t unsubscribe, the email will appear again in your inbox in a few days.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep in your inbox only to the most important stuff, like direct emails, for example. I use filters to help me with this: &lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/2006/03/13/filters"&gt;http://www.43folders.com/2006/03/13/filters&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Process new emails this way:&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you care about this email? Does it requires any action? will you need this email later? If not, Delete it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you think you might need the email in the future (in a very remote future), and you don’t need it now, just archive it. You can easily find it in the future using the search tools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the email requires an action that would take you less than 2 min to be completed, do the action now and then delete/archive the email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archive/delete all emails that are not relevant anymore.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further reading:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.43folders.com/izero"&gt;http://www.43folders.com/izero&lt;/a&gt;: You can find several articles here explaining how to to have an action-based approach to your emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.doist.com/inbox-zero/"&gt;https://blog.doist.com/inbox-zero/&lt;/a&gt;: Pros and cons of using inbox zero method, and a quick summary of what it is.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.superhuman.com/inbox-zero-method/"&gt;https://blog.superhuman.com/inbox-zero-method/&lt;/a&gt;: Looks like a good summary of the inbox zero method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><category term="tech"></category><category term="productivity"></category></entry></feed>